# **AMMAR ALASADI**

## FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

# **ABOUT**

I am a web developer with a background in languages and communication. My goal as a developer is to find creative solutions and designs. I value communication and planning to guide my progress in development. I am a team player with a love of sharing experience and learning.

### **SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, DOM
- Ruby On Rails
- React Node.js Angular.js
- MEAN Stack
- SQL and NoSQL Databases
- MVC Framework
- JavaScript JQuery
- Agile Scrum
- API's -AJAX JSON
- · RESTful programming

## CONTACT

Mobile: (571) 242 1832

E-mail: alasadi.ammar@gmail.com Website: www.ammarcode.com

#### **EDUCATION**

# General Assembly, DC

Web Development Immersive Feb - June 2017

# University of Technology -Baghdad

A.A. in Architecture Design 2006 - 2008

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

WEB DEVELOPMENT STUDENT March - June 2017

I learned web development in agile, scrum environment with a focus on functional programming. I developed full-stack apps is javaScript, Ruby on Rails, MEAN, and Node.js. I had the opportunity to work on a group project to build interactive weather and transportation application in Angularjs. During my studies, I became familiar with version control like Git and GitHub. Improved on the reliability and readability of source code by following best practices. Focused on planning, modeling, and wireframing applications. Visit my website to take a look at my projects.

#### **PGLS**

Arabic linguist 2015 - 2017

I translated material in target languages with a focus on accuracy and details. I also worked with a team of translators to deliver projects, meet deadlines and guarantee client satisfaction. During my time at PGLS, I managed a team of five translators and assigned tasks based on the skills of each team member. I was fortunate to develop a cultural training guide for deployed government officials to help them communicate efficiently and ensure their safety.

#### **CYRACOM**

Arabic Interpeter 2014 - 2017

I Interpreted for a wide range of sectors including medical, legal and social services. I also provided clients cultural education to help them make informed decisions. My main focus was to create a fluid experience between parties and eliminated the language barrier. I was grateful to help clients elevate their concerns by communicating their needs directly.